[Episode 27]
Father, even if I say it a million times,
I want to be with my teacher.
We truly love each other.
Our family has been upright for generations.
You read poetry and books
and learned etiquette,
not to use them to defy human ethics.
If your dear teacher truly liked you,
how could he
personally recommend you as empress?
He must have his reasons.
He promised
that even if he faces public criticism,
- he will still grow old with me.
- Wake up!
- Master!
- Zhi Li.
This is the first time
you have ever slapped me.
Master, Zhi Li.
Both of you, calm down.
Zhi Li, your father
has devoted his life to the country.
When has he ever pursued personal gains?
He is afraid that you will make a mistake
and regret it for the rest of your life.
Mother, since no one cares about my feelings,
I have to plan for myself.
I'm going to see His Majesty now.
- His Majesty has his own ways.
- Stop her!
- Zhi Li.
- Stop this unfilial daughter.
Before the Announcement Ceremony,
you are not to step out of your room.
Move aside.
Zhi Li.
If you step out this door,
you'll get the entire family into trouble.
I don't want you to become a sinner.
I thought only Zhi Li could
stand alongside His Majesty.
I even used the Mandate Token
to force His Majesty.
I never expected...
How can I face His Majesty?
How can I face our ancestors?
After extensive investigation,
this character definitely
refers to the surname Gu.
Although Dou Kou can testify
that Gu Qin killed his wife and father,
we still have no solid evidence
of his collusion with Ling Yun Fei.
Justice eventually comes.
When I hunted down the Society with Di Nian,
I discovered something unexpected.
Tomorrow is Gu Qin's birthday,
so let's give him a surprise gift.
Also,
after he pleads guilty and gets executed,
I will immediately
handle the whole empress thing.
Your Majesty.
There is something I don't get.
Grand Tutor Shen
has always understood Your Majesty best,
and he never
kept a very tight rein on Zhi Li.
Why would he
insist on making Zhi Li the empress?
And that day, outside the Imperial Study,
I also saw your inner struggles.
Was it because of what the Grand Tutor said?
Trust me.
I have never been indecisive about you.
No matter what happens in the future,
I'll clear all obstacles for you in advance.
Your Majesty,
what I desire
has never been the title as an empress,
but a position of power.
Zhi Li was recommended to be empress
and had to leave the Censorate.
I feel terrible about it.
If I became empress, I wouldn't be myself.
I also have to give up my aspirations.
I believe Your Majesty knows
how to weigh and handle it,
but it's too difficult for Your Majesty
to confront the two chancellors,
all the court officials,
and even the Grand Tutor.
Perhaps we should take a step back
and return to a professional relationship.
For both Your Majesty and me,
it might be the best choice for now.
Difficult? Even so, should we just give up?
It's not like you.
And it's not like me either.
I have promised you.
I wish for you to accompany me
through all seasons and festivals.
I will not break any promises
to you ever.
Are you Mo Yu Han of the Blood Moon Society?
Yes.
I'm Zhao Hui, envoy of Beijian,
sent by our ruler for the grand cause.
Tell your ruler
the Blood Moon Society
does not welcome Beijian.
Who exactly are you?
How dare you impersonate me
and kill the envoy
to frame the Blood Moon Society!
Shen Zhi Shu.
You'll never restore your country.
Kill them all. Leave no one alive!
As expected of Ying Gua's lackey,
what a loser!
[Decency]
Young master.
The stupidest thing is
to go on a hunger strike.
It only hurts the people
who care about you most.
Father made your favorite
sweet and sour ribs.
Give it a try.
You all claim to care about me,
but has anyone ever asked
whether my heart hurts?
Then put your hand on your chest
and ask if you have the faintest suspicion.
- And Dou Kou--
- Enough.
I believe what my eyes and ears report.
Zhi Li,
you can choose not to trust anyone,
but can you just trust me this once?
No one wants you to be happy more than I do.
Nian,
do me a favor.
Let me see him.
I want to hear it from him.
If he has deceived me, I will give up.
I would rather you hate me now
than watch you jump off a cliff.
Nian,
the greatest suffering in this world
is not love or hate, but regret.
I'm holding a prince-level banquet for you,
so that it's worthy of your achievements.
This first cup is to celebrate your birthday.
Your Majesty's great grace is unprecedented.
I am deeply grateful and happy.
Congratulations, Lord Gu.
I have also prepared a small gift for you.
It will be presented at the best time.
Please wait a moment, Lord Gu.
Very thoughtful of you, Director Meng.
For a woman,
it is rare to hold the position of Director.
You also have good manners.
It's quite praiseworthy.
Congratulations, Lord Gu.
Someone.
This is the birthday gift I got for you.
I believe you'll like it.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
[Records of Loyal Officials]
Records of Loyal Officials.
[Good Chancellor of Ning Empire]
Your Majesty!
I have an important matter to report.
Your Majesty,
I should not have disturbed you,
but the coronation ceremony is imminent.
If I don't come today,
there will be no turning back.
Rise and speak.
Master.
That day, you gave me a love lock
and made a lifelong commitment.
You asked if I could be brave for you once.
Now, I want to ask
if you will keep your promise.
Your Majesty, I made a mistake.
I failed in my teaching,
causing Zhi Li
to mistake my care for her for love.
It's not true at all about the love lock
or commitment.
It's not true?
So before, you lied
and gave me all those false promises?
Zhi Li, I am very disappointed in you.
Who exactly has tempted you
to fabricate such appalling lies?
You personally gave me this love lock.
You engraved it with your own hands.
How about we verify the handwriting?
You hurt my heart
and deceived me.
Starting today,
I, Shen Zhi Li,
cut all ties with you!
Gu Qin,
you are fond of Shen Zhi Li,
and yet you recommended her
to be the empress.
What exactly are you up to?
Your Majesty, that's not true.
Someone must have
coveted my position of chancellor
and tempted Zhi Li to set a trap to frame me,
wanting to put me to death.
Since you claim to be a good chancellor,
let this booklet show you
what you have done.
Open it!
Fake! It's all fake!
True or not, do you think you can quibble?
The birthday gift for you has also arrived.
Your Majesty.
I'm Dou Kou, Lady Yuan's maid.
I heard Lord Gu
confess his feelings to Miss Shen.
I saw it with my own eyes.
It was him!
He
stabbed my lady
again and again!
Sadly, she was already one month pregnant.
How could he cruelly kill her?
You lowly maid! Nonsense!
Guards!
I'm Xue Leng, a private killer of Lord Gu.
Over the years, he has been threatening me
with the lives of my wife and daughter,
forcing me to assassinate people.
He once ordered me to kill Wan Kai,
but I didn't kill Liu Ru Yan.
He did it himself.
Lord Gu has colluded
with Ling Yun Fei for years.
You filthy rat! This is slander!
I never colluded with a gang leader!
Do you know
why Ling Yun Fei used to escape justice?
That's because Gu Qin,
the so-called "good chancellor",
always covered for him.
Ling Yun Fei was his half-brother,
who had long left their home.
Meng Ting Hui, this is slander!
Gu Qin, you used your official power
to erase household registrations,
making Ling Yun Fei a shadow
that couldn't see the light.
It was also you
who had Ling Yun Fei kill Lord Yuan,
taking all the credit for flood control,
and becoming chancellor.
It was also you
who had Ling Yun Fei control the officials
through female students in gambling houses
and send women from Wanxiang Pavilion
to the colleagues as spies.
You secured your position
at the cost of the lives
of your father-in-law, your brother,
your wife, and your child.
Don't you feel guilty at all?
Take him away.
Gu Qin.
The evidence is solid.
It's time to plead guilty.
Plead guilty?
Why should I?
Lord Yuan could only
write unrealistic policy essays in his room.
With a stroke of his brush,
he took all the glory.
Why?
I killed Lord Yuan,
but in return, I achieved ten years of peace
for the seven prefectures.
Isn't that worth it?
All these court officials
have ever had colleagues' blood
on their hands.
Why should I plead guilty?
Hundreds of thousands of soldiers
achieved peace for the seven prefectures.
How dare you take credit for it!
Gu Qin,
you claim you do it all for the people,
but you never cared about their well-being.
You pave your path to glory
with the blood of others!
Meng Ting Hui, yes, you're upright.
Everyone likes you.
Now you can take the moral high ground
and accuse me and despise me.
But who knows how difficult my path has been?
I was born into a humble family,
with no power or influence.
Anyone could trample over my dignity.
The late emperor only saw Lord Yuan, Xu Ting,
and a few old-timers like Shen Wu Chen.
I endured ten long years
and finally waited for Your Majesty
to ascend the throne.
But you actually want
to replace old officials with new ones.
Now even a woman looks down on me.
If I don't kill those who stand in my way,
what can I do then?
There are quite a few court officials
with humble roots.
You attribute your greed,
ambition, and malice
to others and to this world.
Fine.
Today, let the entire country see
how despicable and disgraceful you are!
That's right.
I am despicable,
disgraceful.
All I want is to climb high,
one step and another,
till I climb my way to the peak of power!
I want to become the second most powerful man
in this country!
I have endured so many years for this day
and killed so many people.
Why can't you just let me get my way?
How could you have such an absurd idea?
How can you turn your grievances
into a reason to kill others?
You tramp!
Even you look down on me?
You're just like Yuan Ling Yi,
relying on family background
to despise and accuse me.
Is this your great grace?
Is this a commendation banquet?
You purposely set me up, Your Majesty!
I have been loyal to the country all my life.
- The Ning Empire failed me!
- How dare you speak of loyalty!
You have been blinded by power.
You colluded with the Blood Moon Society
and gave away the military deployment map.
You have long betrayed the country!
The evidence is conclusive.
Gu Qin, the Right Chancellor,
shall be immediately dismissed.
Exterminate three generations of his family
and announce his crimes to the nation
as a warning to others.
Take him away!
Meng Ting Hui, I will kill you!
You made me do it all! I am innocent!
I am a hero of flood control!
You made me do it all!
Gu Qin, the court's judgment
is not the end of your life.
As a "good chancellor",
you should face the judgment of the people.
I am innocent!
Your Majesty, I'm a hero of flood control!
- Take him away.
- I'm a hero of flood control!
I am innocent! I am a hero of flood control!
Let me go! I am a hero of flood control!
Zhi Li, you are very brave.
If you want to cry, just do it.
Meng,
whenever I close my eyes,
I see the moment he gave me the love lock.
He looked gentle.
It was just a big lie orchestrated by him.
I hate him,
but I hate myself even more.
It's his fault, not yours.
What you did today required great courage.
Very few people can do it.
Everything can start anew.
Zhi Li, your battlefield
doesn't lie in romantic love,
but in the Censorate,
in the official documents,
and in the hearts of the people.
I will be with you.
It's cold. Don't catch a chill.
I want to walk alone for a while.
[Petition Umbrella]
I am the best chancellor of Ning Empire.
Flood control.
Quelling rebellions.
Digging canals.
I single-handedly created a prosperous era.
Meng Ting Hui!
Look at the people.
Look at how much they adore me!
Meng Ting Hui, look!
Look at the people!
Look at how much they adore me!
You must all remember me.
I am the best chancellor of Ning Empire.
I'm Gu Qin.
I'm Gu Qin,
the best chancellor of Ning Empire.
You should all support me.
I'm a hero of flood control!
I'm Gu Qin, the hero of flood control!
A dam broke!
Look! People are dying!
Quick, follow me to fight the flood!
Go carry sandbags to plug the breach!
Come on! Carry sandbags!
With me, the flood cannot harm anyone.
I am a hero of flood control!
I am...
My lord.
Gu Qin has passed away.
He went mad
and drowned himself in the river.
He controlled the waters
and ultimately died in water.
It is indeed the cycle of justice.
Anyway, he was a Right Chancellor.
Director Meng burned the petition umbrella
in the street,
adding fuel to the fire.
The incensed people all watched
how insane and disgraceful Gu Qin was.
How long has Meng Ting Hui been working
in the court?
It has been over three years, my lord.
In these three years, she has acted extremely
and stopped at nothing,
causing turmoil in the court
and loosening the laws.
Although Gu Qin deserves to die,
what he said makes sense.
Now, the new officials are rising,
and the old ones are being snubbed.
I have served three emperors.
Standing at the current court,
I find it utterly unfamiliar.
[Shen Mansion]
Master,
you shouldn't play dumb anymore.
Zhi Li used to be so glorious.
She was the candidate for empress.
Now, the entire capital knows
she met Lord Gu in secret at night
and had an ambiguous relationship
with her teacher.
Cousin, I'm your close relative.
Naturally, I want what's best for Zhi Li.
My nephew is about the same age as Zhi Li,
and he is a scholar.
His wife died of illness two years ago,
and he hasn't remarried.
While he's still willing to marry,
just let Zhi Li marry him.
Zhi Li will never ruin her own life
because of rumors.
Her marriage is her own decision.
Even if she never marries,
we are willing to support her.
So don't trouble yourself.
The tea is cold. Please leave.
Master,
your family now is not what it used to be.
The whole city is spreading rumors
that Zhi Li knew long ago
that Gu Qin killed his wife and child,
and they also say she was an accomplice.
If it's true,
your entire family would be executed.
That demon Gu Qin killed all his family,
and Zhi Li was the one
who personally brought him to justice.
How could she become an accomplice?
If you talk nonsense again,
I'll punch you out!
You're so ungrateful.
Fine, just wait.
Sooner or later,
your entire family will be ruined by Zhi Li.
Get out!
Fine!
I will never come again even if you beg me.
At the banquet,
when Zhi Li exposed that bad guy,
I thought she was just hurt by love,
but now it seems
she was proving her innocence.
Now, the capital is full of rumors.
How can Zhi Li take it?
From now on,
whoever says Zhi Li is an accomplice,
I will risk my reputation
to fight them to the death.
That's right.
Whatever it takes,
we must protect Zhi Li.
If she wants to work cases,
we'll back her up.
If she wants to hide,
we'll take her under our wings.
We will never let anyone hurt her.
Child, be patient.
After the Laba Festival,
it's the Spring Festival.
Have Laba porridge for a few days
till the twenty-third day
of the twelfth lunar month.
[Shen Mansion]
Every Laba Festival,
the house was always full of guests,
and the Grand Tutor was extremely busy.
Today, at this hour,
there isn't even a single guest coming.
Because of what just happened,
those court officials all avoid us.
But Director Meng said
that it was Gu Qin
who deceived our young lady?
But people gossip.
My lady.
Today is Laba Festival.
Wish Father and Mother happiness and health.
Good child, Zhi Li, sit down.
We are family, no need to be formal.
Where is Nian? Why isn't he here?
Captain Di has gone out and not returned yet.
What about Zhi Shu?
He's been gone so long without even a letter.
He has always loved festivals.
This winter is cold.
I fear he can't take good care of himself.
Children have their own things to do.
They've all grown up
and will be independent sooner or later.
Let's eat. The food is getting cold.
Let's eat.
Go ahead.
Try this.
You've been resting at home for so many days.
When do you plan to get back to work?
After the festival, I will go back
to the Censorate.
I will be strict with myself.
Before, I misjudged people
and brought shame to our family.
Zhi Li, we allowed you to become an official,
hoping you could establish yourself
through your talent,
instead of being trapped by romantic love.
Now, don't let any gossip break your pride.
Your father is right.
We never allowed you
to read books on disciplining women
precisely because we didn't want
to constrain your nature.
The other day, your father acted impulsively.
Eat.
Master, Madam, a guest came.
Grand Tutor Shen, Madam Shen,
wish you both happiness and health.
Thank you, Director Meng.
Master, I didn't come as Director.
His Majesty wanted to come,
but he said that given the current situation,
if he could not come to dine with you,
he would feel uneasy.
But if he came in person,
it would put your family
right at the center of the storm.
So His Majesty ordered me
to visit on his behalf.
His Majesty...
I am unworthy of such grace.
His Majesty also said
he would have porridge in the palace
together with your family
to celebrate this festival.
I appreciate it, Your Majesty.
I've conveyed the messages for His Majesty,
but my personal wish is not yet fulfilled.
I was worried about Zhi Li,
so I came uninvited.
I wish to spend this festival with you.
Is that alright?
It's so kind of you.
You are like our family.
We are happy to have you here.
When Fu Zhi returns,
I'll bring her here.
Great.
Then you have to cook
and treat the two children well.
Alright.
Zhi Li, come back to work soon.
Without you,
the tea in the Censorate has no flavor.
Okay.
Nian.
What is this about?
Today, I will move out of the house.
Father, Mother,
when my father died for the country,
I was little.
His Majesty wanted me to inherit his title,
but I felt I didn't deserve it.
Now I have come of age
and achieved some small merits,
so today I asked His Majesty for the title.
I'm moving out of the house
to establish my own household.
Now, I'll formally propose a marriage.
I wish to marry Shen Zhi Li.
What? Nian, why are you suddenly proposing?
You two are siblings!
But we are not blood-related.
I call you Father and Mother
because you kindly raised me.
Now, there is much gossip in the court,
but the Privy Council remains quiet
because the veteran generals there
were once my father's subordinates.
If Zhi Li marries me,
they will speak up for the Shen family.
And no one will slander Zhi Li
and the Shen family.
Nian, we appreciate your kindness,
but this is a matter of your marriage.
How can you decide hastily
because of our family's crisis?
Today, His Majesty sent Director Meng here
to tell the whole country
that His Majesty stands with the Shen family.
The outside criticism will surely subside.
Good child,
marriage is a big matter.
We cannot let you sacrifice it.
You should marry someone you truly love.
Get up.
Father, I have long fallen for Zhi Li.
Zhi Li is like a precious treasure
in my heart.
I cannot watch people judge her at all.
I established my own household
because I want to give her the best.
I know
it's still not enough to prove my sincerity.
So I accept any test you set for me.
Nian,
I watched you grow up.
You have always had courage and principles.
Although you are young,
you have always been steady
in speech and action.
But this time,
I won't arrange Zhi Li's marriage.
Zhi Li chooses her own husband.